<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://defindex.io/blog</id>
    <title>DeFindex Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-11-06T18:37:41.000Z</updated>
    <generator>DeFindex Blog Generator</generator>
    <author>
        <name>DeFindex Team</name>
        <email>hello@defindex.io</email>
        <uri>https://defindex.io</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://defindex.io/blog"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://defindex.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Latest updates, tutorials, and insights about DeFi yield optimization, vault strategies, and blockchain development from DeFindex.</subtitle>
    <logo>https://defindex.io/og-image.jpg</logo>
    <icon>https://defindex.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2026, DeFindex</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Beans integrated DeFindex to drive $610K in stablecoin deposits in 90 days]]></title>
        <id>https://defindex.io/blog/beans-case-study</id>
        <link href="https://defindex.io/blog/beans-case-study"/>
        <updated>2025-11-06T18:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Discover how Beans integrated DeFindex's yield infrastructure in just one week, driving $610K in stablecoin deposits within 90 days while saving over 11 months of development time.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/G1D7DzPW4AAEw6-?format=jpg&amp;name=medium" alt="Beans CEO Wouter Lugard discussing the DeFindex integration" /><br/><br/>
# How Beans integrated DeFindex to drive $610K in stablecoin deposits in 90 days

<div className="grid grid-cols-1 md:grid-cols-3 gap-6 my-8">
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-gradient-to-br from-purple-900/30 to-blue-900/30 rounded-lg border border-purple-500/30">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-200 mb-2">$610K</div>
    <div className="text-sm text-cyan-200">in deposits within 3 months</div>
  </div>
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-gradient-to-br from-blue-900/30 to-indigo-900/30 rounded-lg border border-blue-500/30">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-200 mb-2">1 week</div>
    <div className="text-sm text-cyan-200">integration timeline</div>
  </div>
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-gradient-to-br from-indigo-900/30 to-purple-900/30 rounded-lg border border-indigo-500/30">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-200 mb-2">11+ months</div>
    <div className="text-sm text-cyan-200">of dev time saved</div>
  </div>
</div>

> "We needed DeFi strategies without touching users' funds. We needed rebalancing portfolios to manage multiple DeFi protocols to monetize. That's why we work with DeFindex."
>
> **Wouter Lugard**, CEO at Beans

## Challenge

### Beans needed competitive stablecoin yields without the 12-month build

Every wallet builder eventually faces this decision: offer competitive stablecoin yields to your users, or watch them move to wallets that do.

For Beans—a wallet focused on international remittances for users without blockchain knowledge—the stakes were especially high. Their users in inflation-prone economies were looking for simple, reliable ways to preserve the value of their savings. But building yield infrastructure in-house meant choosing between two impossible options:

<div className="my-6 space-y-4">
  <div className="border-l-4 border-red-400 pl-6 py-4">
    <h4 className="font-bold text-lg mb-2 text-lime-200">Option 1: Build it yourself</h4>
    <p className="text-cyan-100">12+ months of smart contract development, security audits, protocol integrations, and ongoing rebalancing logic. One engineer. Multiple protocols. Endless edge cases. And every week spent building was a week their users earned nothing while competitors shipped.</p>
  </div>

  <div className="border-l-4 border-red-400 pl-6 py-4">
    <h4 className="font-bold text-lg mb-2 text-lime-200">Option 2: Skip the feature</h4>
    <p className="text-cyan-100">Watch users move to wallets that offer yield.</p>
  </div>
</div>

Neither option worked. Beans needed a third way: a partner who'd already solved the problem.

> "Our users don't care about blockchain—they care about saving and sending money safely. We needed yield features that matched that promise without becoming DeFi experts ourselves."
>
> **Wouter Lugard**, CEO at Beans

---

## Solution

### DeFindex abstracts the entire yield infrastructure stack

Beans didn't need to become DeFi protocol specialists. They needed working infrastructure that integrated in days, not quarters—a way to offer users competitive returns on their USD balances without leaving the app.

DeFindex delivered exactly that: battle-tested yield infrastructure as a service.

> "We built DeFindex because we saw wallet teams facing the same impossible choice: spend a year building DeFi infrastructure or skip competitive yield features entirely. Our infrastructure eliminates that tradeoff—wallets get production-ready yield in weeks, not quarters."
>
> **DeFindex Team**

Here's what DeFindex handled so Beans could focus on their users:

<div className="my-8 space-y-6">
  <div className="bg-gradient-to-r from-purple-900/30 to-transparent p-6 rounded-lg border-l-4 border-purple-400">
    <h4 className="font-bold text-xl mb-3 text-lime-200">💰 Safe, stable yield strategies built on USD-based assets</h4>
    <p className="text-cyan-100">Automated strategies delivering up to 62% APY without liquidation risk, all managed through smart contract vaults.</p>
  </div>

  <div className="bg-gradient-to-r from-blue-900/30 to-transparent p-6 rounded-lg border-l-4 border-blue-400">
    <h4 className="font-bold text-xl mb-3 text-lime-200">🔒 Zero custodial risk</h4>
    <p className="text-cyan-100">Smart contract vaults manage funds independently. Beans never touches user deposits, eliminating custody liability and regulatory complexity.</p>
  </div>

  <div className="bg-gradient-to-r from-indigo-900/30 to-transparent p-6 rounded-lg border-l-4 border-indigo-400">
    <h4 className="font-bold text-xl mb-3 text-lime-200">🎨 Plug-and-play UI/UX components</h4>
    <p className="text-cyan-100">Pre-built interface elements that integrate directly into the Beans wallet experience. No months of frontend development required.</p>
  </div>

  <div className="bg-gradient-to-r from-green-900/30 to-transparent p-6 rounded-lg border-l-4 border-green-400">
    <h4 className="font-bold text-xl mb-3 text-lime-200">⚡ One-week integration timeline</h4>
    <p className="text-cyan-100">API and SDK ready to implement versus 12+ months building in-house. From kickoff to staging in two weeks, live in three.</p>
  </div>
</div>

> "We needed rebalancing portfolios to manage multiple DeFi protocols to monetize. That's why we work with DeFindex. They've already solved the hard problems."
>
> **Wouter Lugard**, CEO at Beans

### Integration: From start to live in three weeks

The timeline moved fast because DeFindex's infrastructure was production-ready:

<div className="my-8 bg-gradient-to-br from-cyan-900/30 to-blue-900/20 p-8 rounded-xl border border-cyan-800/30">
  <div className="space-y-6">
    <div className="flex items-start gap-4">
      <div className="flex-shrink-0 w-12 h-12 bg-purple-600 text-white rounded-full flex items-center justify-center font-bold text-lg">1</div>
      <div>
        <h4 className="font-bold text-lg mb-1 text-lime-200">Week 1: API Integration</h4>
        <p className="text-cyan-100">API integration and initial implementation</p>
      </div>
    </div>

    <div className="flex items-start gap-4">
      <div className="flex-shrink-0 w-12 h-12 bg-blue-600 text-white rounded-full flex items-center justify-center font-bold text-lg">2</div>
      <div>
        <h4 className="font-bold text-lg mb-1 text-lime-200">Week 2: Battle Testing</h4>
        <p className="text-cyan-100">Full staging environment testing—"battle testing with weird numbers and stuff like that," as the Beans team described it</p>
      </div>
    </div>

    <div className="flex items-start gap-4">
      <div className="flex-shrink-0 w-12 h-12 bg-indigo-600 text-white rounded-full flex items-center justify-center font-bold text-lg">3</div>
      <div>
        <h4 className="font-bold text-lg mb-1 text-lime-200">Week 3: Go Live</h4>
        <p className="text-cyan-100">Co-marketing alignment and live launch</p>
      </div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

For Beans, this meant their developers stayed focused on user experience while yield optimization happened automatically behind the scenes. Zero months learning Soroban smart contract development. Zero security audits to commission. Zero protocols to vet and monitor manually.

> "The integration was straightforward because we've built DeFindex specifically for wallet teams who don't want to become DeFi experts. Our SDK and API handle all the complexity—vault management, strategy optimization, protocol rebalancing—so partners like Beans can focus on their users."
>
> **DeFindex Team**

**Zero operational risk to Beans.**

---

## Results

### $610K in deposits, competitive yields shipped, 11+ dev months saved

Within three months of launching DeFindex-powered yield features, Beans users had deposited **$610,000 in stablecoins**.

But the numbers tell only part of the story. In emerging markets where Beans operates, competitive yields aren't a nice-to-have feature. They're essential infrastructure for users navigating currency volatility and seeking alternatives to traditional banking that often fails them.

> "DeFindex vaults fit our promise to users: tested, reliable infrastructure that helps them grow stablecoin savings inside the Beans wallet. Our users see returns. We see revenue. And we never had to build the underlying complexity."
>
> **Wouter Lugard**, CEO at Beans

Beyond user deposits, Beans now generates incremental revenue from every user who saves through DeFindex-powered vaults—without building or maintaining the underlying infrastructure. As yield strategies optimize automatically across protocols, Beans benefits from shared economics without ongoing engineering overhead.

The alternative? Twelve months minimum to build, audit, and launch similar functionality in-house. By the time they'd have shipped, the competitive window would have closed and users would have already moved to wallets offering yield.

> "You can't compete in emerging markets without competitive stablecoin yields. DeFindex let us ship that feature in weeks instead of quarters."
>
> **Wouter Lugard**, CEO at Beans

---

## About Beans

<div className="my-8 bg-gradient-to-br from-purple-900/20 via-blue-900/20 to-indigo-900/20 p-8 rounded-xl border border-cyan-800/30">
  <div className="grid grid-cols-1 md:grid-cols-2 gap-6">
    <div>
      <div className="text-sm text-cyan-400 mb-1">Industry</div>
      <div className="font-semibold text-cyan-100">Fintech / Web3 Wallet</div>
    </div>
    <div>
      <div className="text-sm text-cyan-400 mb-1">Focus</div>
      <div className="font-semibold text-cyan-100">International remittances</div>
    </div>
    <div>
      <div className="text-sm text-cyan-400 mb-1">Users</div>
      <div className="font-semibold text-cyan-100">Emerging markets without blockchain knowledge</div>
    </div>
    <div>
      <div className="text-sm text-cyan-400 mb-1">Headquarters</div>
      <div className="font-semibold text-cyan-100">Netherlands</div>
    </div>
  </div>
</div>

---

<div className="my-8 p-8 py-8 bg-gradient-to-br from-cyan-900/40 via-purple-900/30 to-blue-900/40 rounded-2xl text-center backdrop-blur-sm">
  <p className="inline-block text-cyan-100 text-lg px-4 py-4 font-familjen-grotesk font-bold mb-6">Ready to offer stablecoin yields without the 12-month build cycle?</p>
  <a href="https://defindex.io/"
    className="inline-flex items-center justify-center rounded-3xl px-6 py-4 bg-lime-200 transition-all duration-normal hover:scale-105 hover:shadow-lg active:scale-95 mb-8">
      <span className="m-0 p-0 leading-none font-manrope font-extrabold text-sm text-cyan-900">Learn more about DeFindex</span>
  </a>
</div>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>DeFindex Team</name>
            <email>hello@defindex.io</email>
        </author>
        <category label="DeFi"/>
        <category label="DeFi"/>
        <category label="Stablecoins"/>
        <category label="Integration"/>
        <category label="Yield"/>
        <category label="Fintech"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Seevcash Achieved 400% TVL Growth in One Week With DeFindex]]></title>
        <id>https://defindex.io/blog/seevcash-growth</id>
        <link href="https://defindex.io/blog/seevcash-growth"/>
        <updated>2025-01-05T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Ghanaian fintech integrated production-ready DeFi yields in 1 week instead of 12+ months, then watched TVL spike 433% following marketing activation.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://defindex.io/blog/seevcash-growth/seevcash-case-study-cover.webp" alt="Seevcash TVL growth chart showing 433% increase" /><br/><br/>
**A Ghanaian fintech integrated production-ready DeFi yields in 1 week instead of 12+ months, then watched TVL spike 433% following marketing activation.**

## Snapshot

<div className="overflow-x-auto my-8">
  <table className="w-full border-collapse">
    <thead>
      <tr className="border-b border-cyan-500/20">
        <th className="text-left p-4 text-lime-200">Metric</th>
        <th className="text-left p-4 text-lime-200">Result</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr className="border-b border-cyan-800/30">
        <td className="p-4 font-semibold text-cyan-100">Integration Time</td>
        <td className="p-4 text-cyan-100">1 week (vs. 12+ month in-house estimate)</td>
      </tr>
      <tr className="border-b border-cyan-800/30">
        <td className="p-4 font-semibold text-cyan-100">TVL Growth</td>
        <td className="p-4 text-cyan-100">433% in one week post-marketing launch</td>
      </tr>
      <tr className="border-b border-cyan-800/30">
        <td className="p-4 font-semibold text-cyan-100">Code Reduction</td>
        <td className="p-4 text-cyan-100">50%+ through SDK adoption</td>
      </tr>
      <tr className="border-b border-cyan-800/30">
        <td className="p-4 font-semibold text-cyan-100">Time to White-Label</td>
        <td className="p-4 text-cyan-100">6 weeks from launch to first B2B partner</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
</div>

## Background

Seevcash is a mobile-first fintech platform serving Ghana's underserved markets, where 40% of the population remains unbanked but mobile penetration exceeds 140%. The company's mission centers on payment accessibility - including a unique feature where users watch ads to offset transaction fees, removing barriers where every cedi matters.

Recently awarded Stellar Foundation marketing grants, Seevcash needed competitive yield features to retain users in West Africa's fast-moving fintech landscape. Without them, users would migrate to competitors offering returns that outpace local inflation.

## Challenge

Seevcash's users were clear: they wanted competitive returns on stablecoin holdings. But the technical reality was daunting.

Patrick, Seevcash's lead engineer, described the core problem:

> "Most wallet builders don't know smart contracts. For us, it's very time-consuming to develop something like this. We don't even see the solution until someone shows us it exists."

**The barriers were threefold:**

### Time Anxiety

Building comparable infrastructure in-house would require 12+ months: learning Stellar smart contracts, building vault infrastructure, conducting security audits, and implementing sponsorship flows. For a small team focused on core wallet features, that timeline was impossible.

### Technical Complexity

The team would need to understand underlying DeFi protocols, assess liquidation risks, create rebalancing strategies, and handle ongoing protocol monitoring - expertise far beyond their core competencies.

### User Experience Friction

Users would need to acquire XLM for gas fees - a deal-breaker in markets where even small amounts matter. Without Stellar's sponsorship flow, each transaction would require users to manage blockchain complexity directly.

Dawit, Seevcash's founder, summed it up:

> "Time is the main problem. Even if we had the capability, dedicating that much engineering time means delaying everything else our users need."

## Solution

At Stellar's Meridian Conference in Rio de Janeiro (September 2024), the Seevcash team discovered DeFindex offered battle-tested yield infrastructure they could white-label in days.

### Week 1: API Integration

Patrick's team integrated DeFindex's REST API immediately after returning from Brazil. The API handled complex DeFi interactions behind the scenes - automated deposits into Blend Capital, real-time APY calculations, secure withdrawals, and smart contract risk management.

> "I remember arriving back in Ghana and showing Esteban, 'Hey, we actually have the integration done.' It took us one week."

### Weeks 2-4: SDK Migration

As adoption grew among internal testers, the team migrated to DeFindex's SDK to leverage Stellar's sponsorship flow - eliminating gas fees entirely.

The impact was immediate. "The SDK cut our codebase by more than 50%," Patrick explained. "The workload is handled by DeFindex. We just take advantage of the simplicity."

**What the SDK enabled:**

- Zero gas fees for users through sponsored transactions
- One-tap deposits and withdrawals with complexity abstracted completely
- Dramatically reduced code with fewer potential bugs
- Example repositories that turned multi-day implementations into hours

Patrick was emphatic: "Looking at the current integration we have now, that should be a day's work. It's plug and play."

## Results

<div className="grid grid-cols-1 md:grid-cols-2 gap-6 my-8">
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-cyan-950/50 rounded-xl border border-cyan-500/20">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-400">86%</div>
    <span className="text-cyan-200 mt-2 block">Time Reduction</span>
  </div>
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-cyan-950/50 rounded-xl border border-cyan-500/20">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-400">433%</div>
    <span className="text-cyan-200 mt-2 block">TVL Growth</span>
  </div>
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-cyan-950/50 rounded-xl border border-cyan-500/20">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-400">50%+</div>
    <span className="text-cyan-200 mt-2 block">Code Reduction</span>
  </div>
  <div className="text-center p-6 bg-cyan-950/50 rounded-xl border border-cyan-500/20">
    <div className="text-4xl font-bold text-lime-400">6 weeks</div>
    <span className="text-cyan-200 mt-2 block">To White-Label Partner</span>
  </div>
</div>

### 86% Time Reduction

**Traditional approach:** 12+ months estimated

**DeFindex approach:** 1 week initial, 1 day with SDK templates

The difference freed Seevcash's engineering team to focus on features that actually differentiate them in the Ghanaian market.

### 433% TVL Growth in One Week

After six weeks of internal testing, Seevcash activated marketing in early November 2024. The results were immediate.

- **Sept 14 - Nov 1:** Steady $2-3K baseline during internal validation
- **Nov 2-9:** Explosive growth to $13K peak (433% increase)
- **24 active users** earning yield across income levels
- **No minimum investment** required - true accessibility

![Seevcash Vault TVL growth chart showing hockey stick growth from $2K to $13K between Nov 2-9](/blog/seevcash-growth/seevcash-growth-dashboard.webp)

### The Trust-Building Moment

The numbers tell only part of the story. In emerging markets, trust matters more than APY.

> "I've had every single person who deposited ask me, 'Is it real?' When they see the money adding up after just five minutes, they always ask. I tell them, 'Yeah, you can withdraw it as well.' That builds trust immediately." — Dawit, Founder

The ability to deposit small amounts, see real-time earnings, and withdraw instantly transformed skepticism into confidence.

### Internal Adoption First

Before external marketing launched, Seevcash had their own validation metric.

> "For me, the metric to know we're building something very good is when my co-founders and engineers begin using it just like me. When I realized Patrick is now keeping his money in his wallet, I knew other people would use it too." — Dawit, Founder

The signal proved accurate. Seevcash's CTO now holds over $4,000 in the platform - significant savings in the Ghanaian context.

### White-Label Validation in 6 Weeks

Within six weeks of launching yield features, a financial services partner in Ghana approached Seevcash wanting to white-label the same integration.

> "We already have a client who wants this integration through their platform, then to DeFindex. We've already started onboarding third parties." — Patrick, Lead Engineer

This unsolicited B2B expansion proved three critical points: the integration is genuinely simple enough to resell, market demand is strong enough that competitors see the feature as necessary, and DeFindex's infrastructure model works at scale.

### 50% Code Reduction

The SDK migration delivered unexpected engineering benefits beyond speed.

> "We're less likely to create bugs now because the codebase is so much smaller and cleaner. The SDK made things much more streamlined." — Patrick, Lead Engineer

For a small team where every engineering hour counts, cleaner code means faster feature velocity and fewer production incidents that erode user trust.

## What DeFindex Actually Handles

To understand the value proposition, consider what Seevcash avoided building:

**Smart Contract Infrastructure:** Vault management, strategy logic, emergency rescue functionality, role-based access controls

**Protocol Integration:** Connecting to yield sources, monitoring protocol health, handling upgrades, rebalancing when yields shift

**User Experience:** Stellar sponsorship for gasless transactions, real-time APY calculations, transaction history, secure withdrawals

**Ongoing Maintenance:** Security monitoring, protocol evaluation, SDK updates, documentation

DeFindex handles all of this, letting Seevcash focus on accessible financial experiences for Ghanaian users.

## The Bottom Line

Seevcash transformed a 12+ month infrastructure project into a one-week integration, achieved 433% TVL growth in one week following marketing activation, and signed their first white-label partner within six weeks.

The difference? Recognizing that yield infrastructure should be a commodity, not a competitive advantage.

> "I think what makes our partnership work isn't just the product or the yield. It's that Esteban and Francisco can be trusted. Business is built on trust. Everything else is a bonus." — Dawit, Founder

## Ready to Launch Yield Features in Days, Not Months?

See how DeFindex can help your platform offer competitive yields without the development overhead.

**[Schedule a Technical Demo →](https://defindex.io/contact)**

---

**About Seevcash:** A Ghanaian fintech platform democratizing financial access through mobile-first experiences. Recently awarded Stellar Foundation marketing grants for West African expansion.

**About DeFindex:** White-label yield optimization infrastructure on Stellar, enabling wallet providers to offer competitive DeFi yields without building complex infrastructure in-house. Built by PaltaLabs, backed by Stellar Community Fund.]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>DeFindex Team</name>
            <email>hello@defindex.io</email>
        </author>
        <category label="News"/>
        <category label="Case Study"/>
        <category label="TVL Growth"/>
        <category label="Integration"/>
        <category label="Stellar"/>
        <category label="DeFi"/>
    </entry>
</feed>